Guide to the Metropolitan Council on Housing Records TAM.173
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series VI: Audio, 1978-1982; 478650; 1 Linear Feet
  - Phillis Spiro - Open Housing Center and Jane Benedict WBLS (Side 1). Curtis Truehart and Jane Benedict WBLS (Side 2)., May 6, 1980 & June 29, 1980; 478841 (Box 55)
  - Tenants Fight for Survival: Jane Benedict and James Haughton (Side 1). Tenants Fight for Survival: Jane Benedict and Richard James (Side 2)., Jun 8, 1980 & Jun 22, 1980; 478845 (Box 55)
  - Tenants Fight for Survival: Richard James (Grilevell Tenant Association) and Jane Benedict WBLS (Side 1), June 15, 1980; 478847 (Box 55)
  - Tenants Fight for Survival: Jane Benedict and Bob Marrero (Side 1). Tenants Fight for Survival: Bess Stevenson and Bob Marrero - Fuel Passalong-leases (Side 2)., Jul 13, 1980; 478848 (Box 55)
  - Tenants Fight for Survival: guest Curtis Trueheart (Side 1). Tenants Fight for Survival: guest Tom Granger (Side 2)., Jul 20, 1980 & Jul Tenants Fight for Survival: guest Curtis Trueheart (Side 1). Tenants Fight for Survival: guest Tom Granger (Side 2). 27, 1980; 478849 (Box 55)
  - Tenants Fight for Survival: guest Curtis Trueheart (Side 1). Tenants Fight For Survival: guest Curtis Trueheart (Side 2)., Aug 3, 1980 & Aug 17, 1980; 478850 (Box 55)
  - Tenants Fight for Survival: Guest Aurea Rodroquez (Side 1). Tenants Fight for Survival: with Claudia Mausbeck and Jane Benedict., Aug 10, 1980 & Sep 7, 1980; 478852 (Box 55)
  - Tenants Fight for Survival (Side 1). Tenants Fight For Survival: Bob Marrero and Jane Benedict (Side 2)., Aug 24, 1980 & Sep 14, 1980; 478851 (Box 55)
  - Tenants Fight for Survival (Side 1). Tenants Fight for Survival (Side 2)., Sep 16, 1980 & Sep 28 1980; 478827 (Box 55)
  - Wins News Conference- Jane Benedict, Maurice Paprin, and John Dearie (Side 1), Sep 28, 1980; 478725 (Box 55)
  - Jane Benedict "Tenant Survival" with Thomas Granger (Side 1). Jane Benedict- Legislative Wrap-up (Side 2)., Oct 12, 1980 & Oct 19, 1980; 478854 (Box 55)
  - Tenants Fight for Survival: Ray Wallace and Jane Benedict on Carnegie Hall Tenants (Side 1). Tenants Fight for Survival (Chelsea): Anna Cruz, Jane Wood, and Jane Benedict: West 15 Street Building (Side 2)., Nov 2, 1980-Nov, 30, 1980; 478866 (Box 55)
  - Tenants Fight for Survival: guest Bess Stevenson (Side 1).Tenants Fight for Survival: guest Ida Pollack (Side 2)., Dec 28, 1980 & Jan 4, 1981; 478855 (Box 55)
  - Phyllis Spiro - Open Housing Center (Side 1). Tenants Fight for Survival: Review of Heat Crisis, Jane Benedict (Side 2)., Jan 11, 1981 & Jan 25, 1981; 478867 (Box 55)
  - Tenants Fight for Survival: Rent Strike with Curtis Trueheart (Side 1). Jane and Lakeview with Donald Reed (Side 2)., Feb 15, 1981 & Mar 10, 1981; 478856 (Box 55)
  - Tenant Survival: Jane Benedict on J51 ER., Feb 22, 1981; 478853 (Box 55)
  - Tenants Fight for Survival: Met Council on Housing- 250-54 Park Place (Side 1). Tenants Fight For Survival: Met Council on Housing - Gentrification (Side 2)., Feb 21, 1982 & Feb 7, 1982; 478925 (Box 55)
  - "The Tree of Life: A Solution to Inner City Crime, Miseducation & Gentrification" An interview with KANYA founder and director (Side 1). "The Tree of Life: Conclusion", Sep 30, 1982; 478863 (Box 55)
  - Tenants Fight, 28:00., Oct 26; 478828 (Box 55)
  - WSTU Workshop: Nancy Kyriacou-Background Rent Control. Jos Spencer., undated; 478880 (Box 55)
- Series VII: Archived Website, Aug 9, 2009-ongoing; 531453
  The Metropolitan Council on Housing, founded in 1959, is a membership organization dedicated to preserving and expanding New York City's supply of affordable housing. Met Council focuses on preserving rental housing and strengthening tenants' rights. They work through grassroots organizing, lobbying, direct action, including rent strikes, and public education. Met Council has a monthly newspaper (TENANT), a weekly call-in radio show ("Housing Notebook"), forums, and a volunteer-staffed tenant hotline.